Bennett Charles

San Mateo, California <u>bennettcharles100@gmail.com</u> 415.309.7184

Summary

Website and portfolio: https://bennetthub500.github.io/personal/

Technical writer and editor for developer documentation with API experience. Familiar with technical and non-technical audiences. Experienced collaborator with product, design, UX, marketing, sales, engineering.

Authoring and publishing tools: Markdown, reStructuredText, Sphinx, Jekyll, Hugo, Github

Pages, MS Word, MS Sharepoint, Confluence, Quip, WordPress

Technical tools: Github, Postman, Stoplight, OpenAPI, Swagger, JIRA, Pivotal Tracker,

PowerPoint, Zendesk, Freshdesk, Salesforce CRM

Programming: Can read Python, JavaScript

Operating systems: Mac OS, Apple iOS, Windows 10, Android

Online courses: Coding for Writers, Basic Programming (Udemy); Learn API Technical Writing,

JSON and XML for Writers (Udemy)

History

Technical Writer (Open Source volunteer), SaltStack

September 2022 - current

- Contributed to reference docs and developed text and docstring-based documentation templates for Python modules - their functions are similar to API calls - for SaltStack, a remote execution and configuration management product.

Technical Writer, Developer Documentation, Kick Designs

August 2021 - August 2022, San Francisco, CA

- Edited and wrote reference and implementation documentation for security and database clients in a docs-as-code environment using Github and various publishing platforms.

Technical Writer and Communications Consultant

October 2019 - July 2021, San Mateo, CA

- Projects included developer reference and API documentation (REST and GraphQL) for AI/ML startup and content for martech startup.

Communications (Policy Aide), Office of Santa Clara County Supervisor Joe Simitian

February 2018 - July 2019, San Jose, CA

- Directed digital content and outreach strategy, managed website content development and migration for district of 400,000 constituents encompassing Silicon Valley
- Wrote opinion by-lines and press material; curated and edited web content
- Created, edited, wrote new district email newsletter
- Project-managed public events, video and photography production, website design

Tech Communications and Operations Consultant

August 2010 - July 2017

Handle (mobile+web email/to-do app)

- Content for support, community and product, including knowledge base
- Conducted UX lab studies, journey mapping, surveys, customer development interviews
- Launched mobile app to 100,000 users; drove input to roadmap as voice of customer; analyzed user data re: feature adoption & churn

Buyer's Best Friend (web b2b food marketplace)

- Hired, managed, trained data and onboarding team of 10
- Wrote user manuals, managed customer service and Tier 1 and 2 support
- Grew seller catalog 5X "selling" freemium listings; oversaw 9X catalog growth Salesforce
- Dreamforce sales meeting planning between sales teams, customers, and Salesforce subject-matter executives/experts with the Executive Briefing Center team

Principal, Trend Effect Communications

June 2008 - May 2010, San Francisco, CA

- Message development, content, marketing communications, strategic planning services

Director of Marketing, Ops Technology

Sept 2007 - May 2008, San Francisco, CA

- Wrote collateral, presentations, email campaigns, and web content; Managed PR agency

Senior Counselor, Full Court Press Communications

January 2005 - September 2007, Oakland, CA

- Strategic/crisis communications, media relations for public policy and non-profit clients: Calif. Wind Energy Association, Kaiser Permanente, David and Lucile Packard Foundation

Education

M.P.A., Program in Public and Nonprofit Management and Policy New York University

B.A., Psychology University of Rochester